I've come with a request
regarding the story
of Sherlock Holmes
and his nemesis, Professor
William James Moriarty.
Would you kindly
bring it to a close?
As you wish.
[HOLMES]
What's that?
[WILLIAM]
The final location and time.
Also, the address
of another place
that will provide
further answers.
[HOLMES]
Liam.
Why me? Out of all the people.
You composed the mysteries;
my role was nothing more
than to be the detective
who'd solve them.
[HOLMES]
So, why then?
Why did it have to be me?
- -[bell tolling]
- -[WILLIAM] Because--
[WILLIAM]
Our time's up.
[WATSON]
This is an address in the slums.
It's obvious.
There's something here
he wants you to discover.
You should go and
find out what it is.
John, go there with me.
[WATSON] No, you're the
one he delegated this to.
Not me.
This man, you're
going to save him, yes?
I know you'll do whatever
you believe is right.
[HOLMES grunts]
[MORAN]
Hey, Albert.
There's one last thing
I wanted to ask.
[ALBERT]
What is it, Colonel?
[MORAN] It's just, I was
prepared to die with William
and atone for the
crimes we've committed.
Everyone who assembled
here felt the same.
This new plan leaves
Will to take our sins
with him to the grave.
In other words,
he's telling us to live on.
What are you planning to do
with your life... after this?
As survivors, the only
thing we are capable of
doing in our predicament.
[ALBERT] I cannot bear the cross
with him, not now at least.
But I can carry it afterwards.
Passed down from brother
to brother. Shame.
[WILLIAM]
Once the demon is exorcised,
the heart can become pure,
and the curse, lifted.
Mark my words, this
country will be purified.
As a nobleman,
I bet you'd like that,
to see me taken
away in shackles.
[ALBERT] With those words,
you opened up my eyes
and showed me a world
that could be.
Since that day, the plan has
not been altered one stitch.
William, my dear brother,
you anticipated this
outcome from the beginning.
[FRED] Fire! The Lord of Crime
is burning the city down!
[MAN 24A]
The Lord of Crime?
[MAN 24B] Those buildings
are empty, aren't they?
I have been expecting you, sir.
[HOLMES]
What's this?
[HOLMES] Blueprints for
the Noahtic and directions,
enabling Hope
to enter the mansion.
A collection of criminal plans
drawn up by Master William.
A museum, of sorts.
But this final note,
I was told to hand deliver.
[WILLIAM] I'm grateful that
you came this far, Sherlock.
First off, I'd like to thank you
for humoring my request.
As you are aware, my aim is
to assume full responsibility
in regards to this plan.
Slowly, but surely,
I believe my plot will succeed.
The hearts of the people
will be swayed in time.
Alas, I won't be able to
see the results myself,
but that cannot be helped.
Thus, I must
make another request.
[WILLIAM] Amidst this great
upheaval, there will be many
voices that cry out for
help and receive none.
So, I would ask
that you help them.
[WILLIAM] One more thing,
when I came to call on you...
[WILLIAM] ...you likely
left me with a question.
Something along the
lines of, why you?
Giving a single reason
would prove rather difficult.
But let it suffice to say,
our first meeting
was enjoyable enough
for me to forget my plan,
for a moment at least.
[WILLIAM] It felt as though
I had found the one person
who understood me.
Had our circumstances
been different,
I would have liked to converse
with you at great length.
For reasons I
can't quite explain,
it feels as though you're
a long-standing friend.
That is why
I want you at my side
at the moment I meet my end;
no one else will do.
[WILLIAM] If only we could
be reborn in another world.
Perhaps, in the next life,
things will be different.
If only, Liam.
Genius couldn't tell I felt
the same way this whole time.
[growls] The bloody fool!
[NOBLES murmuring]
Quite an ominous sight.
From what I've heard,
the Lord of Crime has been
setting fires all over London.
[TOWNSEND]
The Lord of Crime?
[NOBLEMAN 24A]
No need to worry, though.
Thankfully, all of the fires
are confined to the slums.
Just the slums, eh?
Moriarty has the nobility on
edge thinking we're his enemy,
but it turns out the man's
bloodlust is egalitarian.
[TOWNSEND, NOBLEMEN laugh]
[EMPLOYEE 24A]
Lord Townsend, sir!
[TOWNSEND, NOBLES panting]
[TOWNSEND]
What do you mutts want?
Please, Lord Townsend!
The fires are out of control;
we need to use the water
from the loading
dock to put them out!
[TOWNSMAN 24B] The mansions
completely surround the river!
There's no place
for us to draw it from!
[TOWNSMAN 24C] But if you
let us pass through your gate,
we'll have a fighting
chance of stopping the flames!
Please, sir! We're begging you!
[TOWNSEND]
Off with you!
As if I would allow a rabble
to set foot on my property!
But, sir, please.
Away with you! If you do not
leave this very instant,
then you can consider
yourselves unemployed
come tomorrow morning!
[TOWNSPEOPLE gasp]
The flames are getting closer!
[TOWNSMAN 24A]
We're begging you, Lord Townsend!
Open the gate! Please!
Before it reaches us!
At this rate, we'll all be--
The city of London will be--
[NOBLES gasp]
[TOWNSEND]
Stop that! What are you doing?
[NOBLES gasp]
You won't open up.
So we'll have to get through
and reach the water on our own.
Did you not hear me, man?!
You will not overrun my estate!
Someone, stop them!
[MORAN] Just which side
is hard of hearing?
London is burning,
and these people are
asking for your help.
If nothing is done,
everything will turn to ash,
and this country is finished.
"Noblesse oblige," the mandatory
obligation of the nobility.
While we've all risked our
lives to put out the fire,
you rich have done nothing.
So which of us here
are the true nobility?
[TOWNSEND grunts]
Silence!
We are noblemen
and women by birth,
bearing highborn blood!
Whereas you lot are simply--
[MORAN]
Let me ask you.
Were your ancestors
born into the nobility?
Of course not, they gave
everything for this country.
Those offerings differ
based on one's position
and what they have to sacrifice.
How they think, how they act,
and accept responsibility.
That's what made one a noble,
not their birth,
or how wealthy they were,
but their willingness to make
sacrifices for their country.
[NOBLES murmur]
[TOWNSPEOPLE gasp]
[TOWNSEND]
Keep those buckets coming!
[NOBLES]
Yes, sir!
[TOWNSPEOPLE murmur]
Somehow, we put it out.
[NOBLEMAN 24B grunts]
It's a miracle.
[MORAN] All is proceeding
as planned, William.
Just one thing left.
The finale.
[TOWNSPEOPLE murmuring]
[NOBLEMAN 24C] Wh-What was
that burst of light just now?
[TOWNSMAN 24C]
Look! Atop the bridge!
[TOWNSMAN 24D]
Isn't that...?
[TOWNSMAN 24C]
It's Sherlock Holmes!
[NOBLEMAN 24C] And the other man
is Moriarty, the Lord of Crime!
[TOWNSMAN 24D] Holmes has
got the scoundrel cornered!
You have arrived precisely
on time, Sherlock. No surprise.
Years of planning,
all leading up to this moment.
Using the fires to make the
nobility and the townsfolk
overcome their class barrier
in defense of their city.
[HOLMES]
And then, standing together,
they focus their collective
rage at one target.
All of London considers
you to be a devil, Liam.
[HOLMES]
But there is still time.
Come with me.
Together, I know we
can find a solution
that doesn't end in death!
[WILLIAM sighs]
I'm beyond redemption,
yet still you try to tempt
me to cling to life!
[WILLIAM] If there is
a devil here, it's you!
[WILLIAM yells]
[BOTH grunting]
[MORAN] Louis, are you
sure you want to watch this?
[LOUIS] I requested Holmes'
services in this matter...
...to save Brother.
I'm only here to
see things through,
until the curtains fall.
I gave up my entire life for
Brother, to further his ideals.
I did not mind knowing
death was a certainty,
as long as we
could die together.
[LOUIS] That was before, he
decided he needed to die alone.
One thought terrified me,
being left behind,
alone in this world.
I was convinced there
would be no point in going on.
I had absolutely nothing to
call my own, no possessions.
Whenever I had these thoughts,
Brother would always step in
and affirm my existence.
Reassuring me I deserved
to be a part of this world.
No matter the conclusion
that is reached tonight,
I know that I will
live to see tomorrow.
[LOUIS]
The truth is,
if any single person
acknowledged my existence,
I could go on living.
[LOUIS] And if Holmes
is that man for Brother,
the same way Brother has
been for me, that's enough.
They've all seen us now,
witnessed the
great detective battling
against the Lord of Crime.
The time has come.
Do you really expect me to
stand by and watch you die?
A mind like yours and
that's your idea of atonement?
It's simply a means of
avoiding your own suffering!
Don't use death
as an escape act!
You're not past redemption--
you're just taking
the easy way out!
Live and atone for
what you've done.
Liam, take my hand and live.
[HOLMES gasps]
[HOLMES]
You stubborn jackass!
[HOLMES groans]
You're mad. Why would
you try to save me?
[HOLMES]
Isn't it clear?
Because, William Moriarty,
you are my friend.
[WILLIAM grunts]
[HOLMES] Existence may be
a bitter venture for you,
but not for the world
you've brought about.
It's a place worth
living in, I'm sure of it!
That future--
Our future could
be yours as well!
Experience it for yourself!
So, climb up and live!
[WILLIAM]
I'm a fool.
You didn't come
here as a detective,
but rather, as a friend.
You've bested me, Sherly.
[gasps]
[yells]
You idiot, as if
that would stop me!
Sorry, you can't.
Both of us, we have to live.
[LOUIS]
Three months have now passed.
Albert has
relinquished his fortune
to begin a recovery effort,
the family name
was kept out of it.
Additionally, several
other aristocrats
have contributed
to the fund as well.
Despite a large-scale search
effort undertaken by the Yard,
William's body was never
recovered from the river.
[LOUIS]
However, I'm sure...
[MYCROFT]
Ah, so you showed up.
[LOUIS grunts]
Is this...?
[MYCROFT]
Yes.
It's a collection of all the
incidents put into story form.
Soon it will be going on sale,
but I received a copy
from the author, Doctor Watson.
There is no cause to worry.
I have read it.
Concerning the villain,
Professor Moriarty
is evil personified.
How curious.
Seems he penned the work
with full knowledge of
what actually transpired.
On behalf of Great Britain,
I offer my heartfelt
gratitude to you
and your three brothers.
Sherlock pushed a
secret arrangement,
one that would abolish
the House of Lords
superiority over
the House of Commons.
A deal only possible
through your actions.
We have something in common.
As the Holmes bear their crime,
so must the Moriarty's
from now on.
As punishment, will you carry
it with you in perpetuity?
[LOUIS]
Yes. I will live.
No, we will live
to pay for the crimes we have
committed against Great Britain.
[ALBERT] I was the one who
asked my brother, William,
to carry out this conspiracy.
The blame for these events
begins and ends with me,
Albert James Moriarty.
I am prepared to
accept the punishment
and to also answer
in William's place.
[MYCROFT] There are several ways
one can assume responsibility.
Imposing such a great
punishment on himself--
that is very much his style.
However...
...he is not alone.
Serving this country to
atone for one's crimes
takes many forms.
Louis, are you sure about this?
[LOUIS] Yes, my convictions
remain unchanged.
[MYCROFT]
If you insist.
[MYCROFT] Louis James Moriarty,
I hereby commit to you
the newly-created agency
for intelligence,
which does not officially exist,
and answers directly
to Her Majesty, MI Six.
[LOUIS]
I believe with all my heart
William is still
alive, which is why
I must preserve
the legacy he created
and protect this
promising new world.
That is my mission,
as long as I live.
Valkommen.
[HOLMES]
Scotch.
Sir, you do know
you're in Switzerland?
[BARTENDER 24A] We drink
kirsch here. Give it a try.
[BARTENDER 24A] I doubt you're
this far into the countryside
on business. Are you out
here chasing after a woman?
Hardly.
I'm looking for a friend.
What sort of friend?
[HOLMES]
Well, let's see.
The kind who would look up
at a spiral staircase
and check for the golden ratio.
Anyone you know? [chuckles]
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[WILLIAM] Catch me if
you can, Mister Holmes.